John Dickinson papers LCP.Dickinson
Library Company of Philadelphia
- Series I. John Dickinson
  - Subseries I. Correspondence
    - A. Incoming
      - Letters to William Livingston from [Joshua] and Isaac Vanderbuck; to Thomas Mifflin from George Ross; and to Caesar Rodney from Nathaniel Greene, 1782, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - A-F, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - G, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - H, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - I-K, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - L, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - M-N, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - R, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - S-Z and anonymous, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Envelopes and calling cards, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Notes made by Sally Norris Dickinson regarding John Dickinson's incoming correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - B. Outgoing
      - Letters to his parents from London, the Middle Temple, 1753 December 8-1754 March 8 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Letters to his parents from London, the Middle Temple, 1754 March 29-May 25 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Letters to his parents from London, the Middle Temple, 1754 August 1-October 29 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Letters to his parents from London, the Middle Temple, 1755 January 21-February 19 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Letters to his parents from London, the Middle Temple, 1755 April 8-September 30 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Letters to his parents from London, the Middle Temple, 1756 January 8-June 6 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Letters to his parents from London, the Middle Temple, 1756 June 6-August 7 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - 1758-1780 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - 1781 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - 1782 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - 1783-1784 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - 1785-1789 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - 1792-1798 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - 1800-1802 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - 1803-1804 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - 1805-1806 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - 1807 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - A-Z, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Subseries II. Revolutionary and Early National Government papers
    - A. Revolutionary period, 1765-1780
      - Papers concerning the Stamp Act Congress, 1765 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Thomas Jenning's opinion on Maryland poll tax, extract from Virginia Committee of Correspondence proceedings, 1773 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Notes from first Continental Congress, Address of Congress to the Inhabitants of Quebec, 1774 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Address to John Dickinson from the Mechanics, 1774 June 27 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Draft of Patrick Henry's petition to the King, 1774 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Dickinson's draft of first petition to the King, 1774 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Jay's draft of the Olive Branch Petition; resolution on a motion by Lord North, 1775 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Dickinson's note on Constitutional revisions, 1776 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Burke's motions in the House of Commons, 1777 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - State tax resolution, 1779 October 7 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - New Jersey protest of Virginia land policies, 1780 December 29 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Counterfeit money and description of detection, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - East India Tea Company accounts, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - B. Early National period, 1781-1800
      - Charter for the National Bank, 1781 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Papers relating to the Hartford Convention; early land policies, 1781 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Regulations on private armed vessels, 1782 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Act of Assembly on General Steuben; proposed amendments on bills of credit and tax payments, 1782 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Letter concerning relations with Great Britain, 1783 June 24 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - On moving Congress from Philadelphia to Annapolis, Maryland (because of the Mutiny of 1783), 1783 August 13 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Extract of a letter from the Count de Vergennes to Chevalier de la Luzerne, 1783 February 27 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Dickinson's note on the mutiny in Philadelphia; Indian treaty; and extract of letter with Franklin's advice on foreign relations, 1783 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Newspaper clippings on the National Bank and overseas trade, 1784 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Hartley's recommendations on commercial treaty, 1784 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Copies of acts on foreign trade, Western lands, and import duties, 1784 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Ordinance on the Department of Finance, 1784 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Report on Western lands, [1784] (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Dickinson's notes for speeches at the Constitutional Convention, 1787 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Dickinson's notes for speeches at the Constitutional Convention, 1787 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Dickinson's notes on modification of the Randolph Plan, 1787 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - Virginia Plan papers, 1787 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - Notes on the New Jersey Plan, Constitutional Convention, 1787 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - New Jersey Plan papers, 1787 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - Barclay's recommendations, 1787 (Box 6, Folder 33)
      - Dickinson opinion on states' rights to dissent, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
      - On the establishment of the capital at Washington, real estate and stamp taxes, 1798-1800 (Box 6, Folder 35)
      - Copies of Fabius letters supporting the Constitution, 1788 (Box 6, Folder 36)
      - Dickinson draft of a speech on the Jay Treaty, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
      - Statement on the encouragement of American manufactures [by J.M.], undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
      - Financial notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
      - Draft on an act on supply commissions, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
      - Dickinson's notes on the establishment of the national capital, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
      - Dickinson's manuscript on a plan of government to replace the Articles of Confederation, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
      - Dickinson's notes on government affairs, undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
      - Blank letters of marque, undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Subseries III. Revolutionary War documents
    - Furlough recommendations, 1776 Summer (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
    - Petition for furlough, 1776 Summer (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Hospital reports, 1776 Summer (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Soldiers' provisions, ammunition account, 1776 July, August (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Dickinson's notes on military movements; general orders, and memorandum on Longchamps case, 1776 July-August, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Militia returns and Lancaster militia ammunition returns, 1776 August 9-10 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Order for supplies and certificate of loyalty for Samuel Wharton, signed by Benjamin Franklin, 1779, 1780 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Report on galley construction, 1782 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Articles of Peace, 1783 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Instructions on battle tactics, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Subseries IV. Delaware government documents
    - Delaware River land dispute, 1772 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - William Killen resignation from the Supreme Court, 1781 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Bill on a state tax and bills of credit, 1781 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Suggestions for reform of the Delaware court system, submitted by William Killen, 1781 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Bill to recruit a regiment in Delaware, 1781 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Letters of congratulation regarding [presidency] and Dickinson's response to the Assembly, 1781-1782 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - "An Account of the Rejoicings on the Birth of the Dauphin at Dover, June 22, 1782," describing the procession and triumphal arch, 1782 June 19-22 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Militia returns, 1782 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - John Lyle case, 1782 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Memo regarding Navy finances and Congé for M. Hamilton, 1782 August, October (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Paymaster and recruiting accounts, 1782 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Dickinson's appointment to the Court of Appeals, 1788 September 18 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Statement on William Killen, Supreme Court Justice, 1789 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Budget figures, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Subseries V. Pennsylvania government documents
    - Dickinson's speeches, [1760s] (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Dickinson's manuscript for "Protest in the Assembly against the clause for making paper bills of credit a legal tender in payment of all contracts", 1764 March (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Pennsylvania State Convention resolutions, military, 1776 August 10 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Petition to the King regarding tea duty, and John Morris's appointment, 1771 February 12, 1771 March 22 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Materials regarding the Elizabeth Graeme Fergusson case, 1778-1779 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Accounts of the class tax, land office and militia fines and opinion on enforcement of prisoners of war act, 1782 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Letters regarding the financing of the Pennsylvania regiments, 1783 January 4, 8 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Court fines, 1783 January 4, 8 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Soldiers' land claims, 1783 February 16 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Expenses of Robert Ralston and debtors' petition, 1783 April 1, 1783 August 21 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Indian Treaty, 1783 October 4 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - A list of debts due by the State of Pennsylvania and an estimate of the expenses for the year 1783, 1782 December 2 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Letters of congratulation regarding Dickinson's election to the Presidency of Pennsylvania, including responses, 1783 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Celebration of the peace, 1784 January 20 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Proposal for and correspondence regarding a Bank of Pennsylvania, 1784 January-February (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Council notes, 1784 March 22 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Dickinson's draft of "Answer to the Council of Censors", circa 1784 [July] (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Dickinson's speeches, 1784 July 21, 1784 August 5 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Assembly bill on damaged goods and admiralty jurisdiction, 1784 August (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Pennsylvania state financial statement and Indian Treaty, 1784, 1784 October 22 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Memo regarding Captain Stokely and Pennsylvania debt and revenue statements, 1784 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Dickinson's message to the General Assembly regarding public lands, 1784 December 4 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Dickinson's speech to the General Assembly, 1784 December 15 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Tax accounts and salaries of Supreme Court justices, 1784 December (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Dickinson's message on Pennsylvania's fiscal plan, 1784 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Materials regarding the Aaron Doane case, 1784 November-1785 January (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Dickinson's message to the General Assembly, 1785 February 1 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Payment of soldiers, 1785 February 22 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Materials regarding Major James Evans' court martial, 1875 March 24 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Materials regarding Captain Joseph Hoover's court martial, 1785 April 6 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Dickinson's messages and notes regarding Indian affairs, prison conditions, loan repayment, etc., undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Essay on continental and state securities, a debtors' petition, and a motion on committee of safety, undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Papers regarding the military, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Indian treaty, land office records, and proposal for education of poor children, undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Tax and population accounts, undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Exports values compared, undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Production figures, undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence regarding the Wyoming controversy, 1782-1783 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence regarding the Wyoming controversy, 1784, undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Papers regarding the Wyoming controversy, 1782-1784 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Subseries VI. Land and business records
    - A. Miscellaneous land and financial papers
      - Papers concerning the Dickinson property at Poplar Ridge, 1733-1801 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - 1763-1774 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Indenture, John and Mary Dickinson one party, and Philemon Dickinson, the other, 1774; [oversized] (Volume 1)
      - 1777-1778 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Receipt and account book, 1777-1807 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Notebooks on land business and rentals, 1779-1795 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Articles of agreement, 1780-1785 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - 1786-1792 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Newspaper clippings on agricultural and building topics, 1787-1804 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Construction agreements and estimates, 1793 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - 1794 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - 1795 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Delaware rent roll, 1796 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - "Exemplification patent", 1796 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - 1797 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - 1798 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - 1799 January-May (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - 1799 June-December (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - 1800 (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - 1801 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - 1802-1803 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - 1804-1805 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - 1806-1807 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Memoranda on construction work, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Newcastle County, Delaware, deed, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - A Draught of a Parcel of Land (Jones Neck), purchased by Joshua Gordon by Philemon Dickinson, undated; [oversized] (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - An Old Draught of Land in Kent, undated; [oversized] (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - B. Legal papers
      - Wills of Dickinson family members, 1722, 1730 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Will of John Dickinson's (notes and drafts), with codicils, 1780-1803 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Will of Albanus Logan, 1854 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Certificate of admission to the Middle Temple, 1757 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Dickinson's opinions on the state of the laws in America, [1773] (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Dickinson's management of the Thomas Wilson estate, 1774-1776 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Case of the armed sloop Argo, before the High Court of Errors, Pennsylvania, 1783 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Case of Matteo Bratelli, before the High Court of Errors, Pennsylvania, 1784 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Case of Purviance et al v. Angus, High Court of Errors, Pennsylvania, 1785 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous papers concerning Dickinson's legal practice, 1782-1804, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - C. Bills and receipts
      - 1755-1776 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - 1777-1779 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - 1780-1783 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - 1784-1789 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - 1790-1792 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - 1793 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - 1794 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - 1795 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - 1796 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - 1797 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - 1798 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - 1799 January-July (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - 1799 July-December (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - 1800 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - 1801 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - 1802 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - 1803 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - 1804 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - 1805 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - 1806 (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - 1807 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Subseries VII. Collected essays, notes and commonplace books
    - The Concessions of West Jersey, 1676 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Manuscript list of lots in the original draft of Philadelphia, in the hand of Isaac Norris, 1683 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Notebook, in the hand of Isaac Norris, on the Penn-Baltimore land dispute, 1600s (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Account of land partitioning in Germantown, 1715 May 26 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Notes on Dickinson family genealogy, circa 1740, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Copy of Conrad Weiser's journal on Indian Treaty, 1754 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Clippings from the Gentleman's Magazine, largely regarding the preservation of fruits and grains, 1753, 1764, 1769 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - "Opinion on the 40 Poll Act in Maryland," essay probably by Dickinson, 1773 October 1 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Robert G. Hooper essay on Liberality of Sentiment, including cover letters, 1785 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper clippings of advertisements for Dickinson's political writing and [Dickinson's] comment on Pennsylvania land laws, 1799, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Notes on Dickinson's books and papers, 1802, 1885, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - 19th century notes on Letters from a Farmer in Pennsylvania, circa 1800s (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Anonymous essay on the Nottingham School, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Commonplace book [probably belonging to Dickinson], undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Lloyd and Logan genealogies, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - "Reflections on the Flag of Truce Trade in America," by an English Merchant [Dickinson manuscript?], undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Society of Cincinnati regulations, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Speech on the founding of Dickinson College, [circa 1783] (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Subseries VIII. John Dickinson estate records
    - Estate journal, 1808-1814 (Volume 2)
    - Estate ledger, 1808-1814 (Volume 3)
- Series II. Mary Norris Dickinson
  - Copies of letters between Hannah Griffitts, Hannah Harrison, and Mary Norris, circa 1760s (Volume 4)
  - Poems, 1764-1768 (Volume 5)